<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on ShadowMonkey</title>
    <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on ShadowMonkey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ShadowMonkey.pr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Sumcheck</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/zkproofs/on_sumcheck_arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/zkproofs/on_sumcheck_arguments/</guid>
      <description>Outline Motivation What does the sumcheck protocol do? Detailed multivariate sumcheck protocol Discussion of polynomial descriptions Discussion of $\mathsf{check}_{2}$&amp;rsquo;s seeming redundancy Discussion of $\mathsf{check}_{3}$ Analysis of multivariate sumcheck protocol Prover complexity (time, space, communication) Verifier complexity (time, space, communication) Security (completeness, soundness) How to get from an R1CS instance to a Sumcheck Instance How does sumcheck figure into zero knowledge proof systems Matrices to functions Functions to ML polynomials Query reduction to get sumcheck instance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101 Tangential Topics</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_101_tangential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_101_tangential/</guid>
      <description>Tangential Topics Peer-to-Peer In order to avoid centralization, Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer architecture. Unlike in a client-server architecture, nodes in this network act both as a server that can download files and as a client that can process data and message other nodes. This does not mean that the nodes must be identical, but only that there is no hierarchy among them.
Nodes In Bitcoin there are three types of nodes: full nodes, mining nodes, and light nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 101</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_101/</guid>
      <description>Problem I want to send money over the internet but I don&amp;rsquo;t trust financial intermediaries.
Solution Instead of giving a financial intermediary control over the recordbook, distribute the recordbook across a network of participants.
Naive Approach How does one distribute a recordbook across a network of participants? Well, not unlike the internet itself, we can create a network of nodes (participants) that can transmit messages to one another. Each participant in the network can can store its own version of the recordbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 102 (Consensus)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_102/</guid>
      <description>Problem I want to send money over the internet using a distributed network but I don&amp;rsquo;t trust malicious nodes.
Solution Combine consensus protocols to create a Byzantine Fault Tolerant consensus mechanism.
Consensus can probably delete this paragraph In order to add to the ledger, transactions undergo a process to check that they’re legitimate. But, it’d be inefficient to try to process every transaction one-by-one; instead, the transactions are bundled together into blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 103 (Bridges)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_103/</guid>
      <description>Problem I want to send money from one blockchain to another but I don&amp;rsquo;t trust financial intermediaries.
Solution Create a trust-minimized way for blockchains to interact.
Context A blockchain is designed to account for all possible state conditions - the combination of accounts, transactions, data, etc.. It is not designed to interpret information from other systems, the same way a store isn&amp;rsquo;t designed to accept gift cards from other stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 104 (State Machines)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_104/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_104/</guid>
      <description>Problem The distributed network of machines that I use is limited to sending financial transactions. I want to perform other actions with minimized trust.
Solution virtual machine
State Machines The modern concept of a blockchain is to exist as a globally replicated state machine. What this means is blockchains have been designed to run as a single machine where every user action (transaction) is interpreted relative to the state. The term ‘virtual machine (VM)’ refers to running this machine inside another, the same way one could run the Mac OS on a Windows computer using a VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 105 (dApps)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_105/</guid>
      <description>Problem I can write smart contracts to create trustless applications but the user experience (UX) is insufficient for mainstream adoption.
Solution dApps
Tokens https://kydo.substack.com/p/decentralization-in-dapps-vs-l1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 106 (Oracles)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_106/</guid>
      <description>Problem I can create decentralized applications but there is no way for them to interact with real-world data.
Solution Oracles</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 107 (Sovereign Chains)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_107/</guid>
      <description>Problem I can&amp;rsquo;t build my own decentralized network without designing a blockchain from scratch.
Solution cosmos-sdk, polkadot, avalanche: Design a blockchain with custom consensus, validators, token / staking / inflation, custom rules, gas fees, rules built into the chain instead of smart contracts, custom execution environment / devx for developers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain 108 (Rollups)</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_108/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_108/</guid>
      <description>Problem Gas is expensive on Ethereum. or I want more control over my application but I still want to rely on Ethereum security.
Solution Rollups - very unfinished
Context Rollups are a clever workaround to circumvent the high gas costs of transacting on Ethereum. By compressing many transactions into calldata, a rollup can effectively run hundreds of transactions on Ethereum for the price of one. To do this, however, requires another layer (a Layer 2) where these transactions are derived to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Preface</title>
      <link>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_0_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ShadowMonkey.pr/cryptocave/blockchain_0_preface/</guid>
      <description>The set of articles that follow provide a foundation for understanding the world of blockchains and cryptocurrencies in the most concise, correct format I could procure. They are geared towards technical readers with little to no context of this world, but I still find them useful even as a reader with a lot of context. I refer to these articles often when elaborating on the incredible applications of ZK in the ZKWorld section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
